A Guide to the Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel, 1991-2012
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel, 1991-2012
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 6/3/11a
1.9 Cubic Feet; 2 boxes and 1 oversize folder
The Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel include correspondence and reports, photographs and slides, four VHS tapes, three floppy disks, recycling logs, and publications and newspaper articles concerning Virginia Tech Recycling (VTR) and Larry Bechtel's position as its Coordinator from 1991-2007.
Bechtel, Lawrence Reid, 1949-
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Recycling
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in September 2012.
Administrative History
Virginia Tech Recycling (VTR) was started in 1991 by the Physical Plant. As a part of Facilities Services' Office of Energy and Sustainability, Virginia Tech Recycling provides recycling services to Virginia Tech. Initially, Virginia Tech Recycling provided campuswide aluminum can recycling services, eventually expanding to collect corrugated cardboard, sorted office paper, glossy magazines and catalogues, newspapers, and commingled materials.
Biographical Note
Larry Bechtel served as VTR's first coordinator from 1991 through 2007. Bechtel is also a professional sculptor and made the statue of William Addison Caldwell on Virginia Tech's Blacksburg campus.
Scope and Content
The Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel contains several photographs and slides, four VHS tapes, three floppy disks, four books, and a number of reports and newspaper articles concerning Virginia Tech Recycling (VTR) and Larry Bechtel's position as its Coordinator ranging from 1991-2007. VTR reports describe its goals, budgets, and events. The collection also includes a personal account of the progression of VTR by Bechtel, a daily log of the program ranging from 1991-1994, and several memos sent and received during Bechtel's position as Coordinator.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series by material type:
Series I: A/V Materials and Photographs, which is arranged chronologically
Series II: Correspondence, which is arranged in alphabetically by folder title
Series III: Reports, Articles, and Published Materials, which is arranged in alphabetically by folder title
Series IV: Administrative Documents, which is arranged in alphabetically by folder title
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Office of the Virginia Tech Recycling Coordinator, Larry Bechtel by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Recycling (Waste, etc.); University Archives; University History
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Recycling
People:
Bechtel, Lawrence Reid, 1949-
Contents List
- Series I: A/V Materials and Photographs, 102171
  - Landfill Snapshots/Gamma Beta Phi Soil and Water Conservation/Earth Day, May 20, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Old Corrugated Cardboard Truck at Wallace Child Development Lab Photographs, March 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - University of Georgia Physical Plant Photographs, February 19, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Tech Leaf Composting Photographs, February 23, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 8 Cubic Yard Packer Truck and Ford Chassis Photographs, March 17, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Tech Recycling Photographs, July 2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ecocycle! (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wando Earth Ranger, football recycling and VTR history slides (Zip disks) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Landfill Photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Slides (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Guide to the slides (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Congratulations and Thank Yous (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series III: Reports, Articles, and Published Materials
  - Aegis Environmental Audit, November 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural Economics Analysis, 2000-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beyond 40 Percent: Record-Setting Recycling and Compost Programs (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bioconversion Facility: Articles Regarding Design, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bioconversion Facility: Support Materials, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bills; 2006 and 2009 Actions (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Ecodemia: Campus Environmental Stewardship at the Turn of the 21st Century" by Julian Keniry (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "In Defense of Garbage" by Judd H. Alexander (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Montgomery Regional Solid Waste Authority--Mid-County Landfill Closure; Solid Waste Transfer Station (maps) (Folder 1)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Articles, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 2001-2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Redeeming Creation: The Biblical Basis for Environmental Stewardship" by Fred Van Dyke, David C. Mahan, Joseph K. Sheldon, & Raymond H. Brand (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Removed Materials Copy (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Taillores Declaration Documents, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Seeking to Explain the Waste Stream at Virginia Tech: A 'Snapshot' of February Figures" (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Waste Audit Summary Reports, May 26, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series IV: Administrative Documents
  - Appointment Books/Ledgers (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Coordinator Support Documents, 1999-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Recycling Ad Hoc Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Tech Recycling Business, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Virginia Tech Recycling Goals, 1993-2003 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Tech Recycling Logs, 1991-1994
    - July 1991-April 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - April 1992-July 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - July 1992-May 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - October 1993-March 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - March 1994-June 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - June 1994-July 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)